Martin Josefsson, Freelance Software Developer

PROFILE

You learn by getting your hands dirty. By working hard and always staying curious. Since early childhood I've been working and playing with computer. I grew up with the unix shell, and writing shell code. I started to create web sites at age 11, and at 14 I crafted cheats for computer games. After graduating high school in Sweden I went to Berlin to experience the tech scene, and have since worked passionately on web and mobile projects. I like my code well-documented, readable and well-tested.

EXPERIENCE

FOUNDER, FRONT/BACK-END DEVELOPER, REMOTE BITCOIN JOBS 2014
Remote Bitcoin Jobs is a job board I bootstrapped as a side-project in the summer of 2014. I developed the app in Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL, and set everything up around the business from getting a designer, to hosting and development.

JAVASCRIPT & FRONT-END DEVELOPER, BONAGORA GMBH, BERLIN-TOKYO (REMOTE) 2014

I worked with Bonagora developing their MVP. I wrote the web app in Ember.js, jQuery, Bootstrap (for responsive design) and used Jasmine for tests. I was living in Tokyo at the time, and worked remotely. The company was based in Berlin.

FOUNDER, DEVELOPER & DESIGNER, KANA REFERENCE, BERLIN, GERMANY/TOKYO, JAPAN 2013-2014

I was travelling in Japan, and learned basic Japanese. To help study I made a phone app with Cordova/Phonegap, Angular.JS and released it on the App Store. I did the whole project myself, from idea to shipping. It's a small app, and it's sources are available here: https://github.com/fromheten/KaraRef.

JAVASCRIPT & FRONT-END DEVELOPER, GOSUB COMMUNICATIONS GMBH, BERLIN, GERMANY 2013

Worked on a HTML5 game for ZDF, the German public service television network. The game was a companion product for their TV series. We implemented it using <canvas>, Angular.is and Pixi.is.

JAVASCRIPT & FRONT-END DEVELOPER, URLIST, BERLIN, GERMANY 2013 Refactored the front-end code base, added tests and wrote new features. Wrote advanced Javascript and used Backbone.js, underscore.js, jQuery and Jasmine.

RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER, PICKLED OLIVES SOFTWARE, BERLIN, GERMANY 2012-2013

Developed Ruby On Rails applications for clients, using Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Coffeescript, jQuery, Git & Github.

EDUCATION

BÄCKÄNGSGYMNASIET, BORÅS, SWEDEN - HIGH SCHOOL, 2008-2011

SKILLS

Software Development, vast knowledge of Javascript and Ruby in functional and/or object-oriented styles. Worked with Backbone.js, Meteor, Angular.js, Ember.js, jQuery, Underscore, Ruby on Rails & Sinatra. Great at CSS3 and HTML5, and responsive design either with frameworks like Bootstrap or Foundation or without using a framework. Ok with Shell, Python, Java, CocoaTouch, RubyMotion and a little bit of Clojure.